

Andreas Klein

Agile Coaching & Development

COLOGNE, GERMANY / +49 173 8888 987 / ANDY@IXIS.IO / WWW.IXIS.IO

Figuring out how to get Things done in larger Teams as a <u>certified Scrum Master</u>, Mentor or <u>Frontend Developer</u>, not just in the software Industry. I help Agencies and Companies to realize accessible Products with Value and with a Focus on happy People. I also enable <u>Conferences</u> to share Experiences.

Outside of the web, I'm a proud father of two beautiful children, a passionate freestyle skateboarder/snowboarder and I like the taste of good espresso.

If there is still time, I push our nonprofit organization <u>makuyuni.org</u> forward, that build schools in the outback of Tanzania where kids have no ability to go to school!

My other Profiles on the web:



twitter.com/ixisio



github.com/ixisio



xing.com/andreas klein156

Skills

- · Agile mindset
- 10 Years of experience in Frontend Development and Agile Product Development
- Accessibility Workshops and Trainings
- Professional Scrum Master® (PSM)
- Scrum Product Owner (PSPO)
- Moderation and Communication Trainings
- Agile Coach & Mentor
- Scaling Scrum with multiple Teams (Scaled Scrum, LESS, Nexus, SAFe)
- Change Management for Agile Product Development Teams
- · Frontend Development and Consulting
- Design Thinking
- · Workshops, Trainings and Coaching
- Kanban
- Continuous Improvement

Project Experience

HDI AG // Digital insurance products

Customer: Avenga Germany GmbHRole: Agile Coaching, Scrum Master

• Date: 2019 - 2020

https://www.hdi.de

AXA AG // Digital insurance products

- Customer: AXA AG
- · Role: Agile Coaching, Scrum Master
- Date: 2019

https://www.axa.de

Vaillant Group // Connected Devices - IoT, Websites

- Customer: Vaillant Group Business Services GmbH
- Role: Agile Coaching, Scrum Master
- Date: 2017 2018

https://www.vaillant-group.com

Toom Baumarkt // Websites & Shops

- Customer: Rewe Group, Fork GmbH
- Role: Agile Coaching, Frontend Architect
- Date: 2016
- Technologies: Scrum, ES6, React.js

https://www.toom.de/

Aktion Mensch // Accessibility Workshop, Training

- · Customer: Aktion Mensch e.V., Trusted Shops GmbH
- Role: Workshop Speaker
- Date: 2016
- Topics: Accessibility

https://www.aktion-mensch.de/ http://www.trustedshops.de/

Billiger-Mietwagen.de // React Application

- Customer: Billiger-Mietwagen.de, SilverTours GmbH
- Role: Front-Fnd Architect
- Date: 2016
- Technologies: React.js

https://www.billiger-mietwagen.de/

.. Ask me if you want to see the years 2009 to 2015.

Work Experience

2016 - present	Agile Coaching & Development (Freelance) www.ixis.io
2009 - 2016	Front-End Developer (Freelance) www.ixis.io
2011 - 2014	Frontend Developer (nexum AG) www.nexum.de
2009 - 2011	Application Developer eLearning (German Sport University Cologne) www.dshs-koeln.de

Education

2008 - 2011 Study of Physics - University of Cologne (until 2009)

Magisterium

Study of Sports and Performance - German Sport

University Cologne *Bachelor of Science*

1998 - 2007 Comprehensive school, Willy-Brandt Cologne

Graduation from high school



Cologne, last updated 01 April 2020, Andreas Klein